Kate Braid fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Europe interviews, 1984; F-10-2; 3 sound recordings 9 .wav files; Physical description: series contains 3 sound recordings stored on 4 audio cassettes (originals). Audio cassettes have been digitized to .wav format.
  - Non-traditional occupations congress, Denmark, 1984; F-10-2-0-0-0-2; 2 audio cassettes 4 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-2940, Audio cassette OBJ-2941)
    - OBJ-2941_prt2_sideA.wav
    - OBJ-2941_prt2_sideB.wav
  - Danish tradeswomen, 1984; F-10-2-0-0-0-3 (Audio cassette OBJ-2942)
    Sound recordings
    OBJ-2942 Side A is blank and was not digitized.
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: C-10-2-0-3, C-10-2-0-4, F-10-item74, F-10-item75.
    - OBJ-2942_prt2_sideB.wav
- Labour Canada interviews, 1988; F-10-3; 27 cm of textual records 33 sound recordings; Physical description: series contains 33 interviews stored on 68 audio cassettes, including originals and access copies; note that access copies do not exist for all sound recordings. 15 of 68 audio cassettes have been digitized to .wav format.
  In 1988 Kate Braid traveled across Canada interviewing tradeswomen for inclusion in two booklets she produced for Labour Canada -- Building the Future: Profiles of Canadian Women in Trades and Looking Ahead: Profiles of Two Canadian Women in Trades. Series includes audio cassettes, transcripts, notes, drafts of profiles, a logbook, correspondence, government publications and reference material.
  - Allary, Donna transcript and notes, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 10-3)
    Allary, Donna; Textual records
  - Brown, Sandy transcript and notes, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 10-3)
    Brown, Sandy; Textual records
  - Charron, Monique transcript and notes, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 10-3)
    Charron, Monique; Textual records
  - Courval, Marie-Andrée transcript and notes, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 10-3)
    Courval, Marie-Andrée; Textual records
  - Duly, Catherine transcript and notes, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 10-3)
    Duly, Catherine; Textual records
  - Duperre, Danielle transcript and notes, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 10-3)
    Duperre, Danielle; Textual records
  - Ethier, Danielle transcript and notes, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 10-3)
    Ethier, Danielle; Textual records
  - Fickes, Doreen transcript and notes, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 10-3)
    Fickes, Doreen; Textual records
  - Graham, Sheri transcript and notes, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 10-3)
    Graham, Sheri; Textual records
  - Kaake, Sue transcript and notes, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 10-3)
    Kaake, Sue; Textual records
  - Kowalchuk, Lillian transcript and notes, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 10-4)
    Kowalchuk, Lillian; Textual records
  - Lainio, Laila transcript and notes, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 10-4)
    Lainio, Laila; Textual records
  - Longstaff, Lori transcript and notes, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 10-4)
    Longstaff, Lori; Textual records
  - Macfarlane, Sharon transcript and notes, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 10-4)
    Macfarlane, Sharon; Textual records
  - Millar, Jan transcript and notes, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 10-4)
    Millar, Jan; Textual records
  - Nichols, Sandra transcript and notes, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 10-4)
    Nichols, Sandra; Textual records
  - Nutt, Alison transcript and notes, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 10-4)
    Nutt, Alison; Textual records
  - Oakes, Pat transcript and notes, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 10-4)
    Oakes, Pat; Textual records
  - Pratt, Gwen transcript and notes, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 10-4)
    Pratt, Gwen; Textual records
  - Standing, Lynn transcript and notes, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 10-4)
    Standing, Lynn; Textual records
  - Vaughan, Mary Jane transcript and notes, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 10-4)
    Vaughan, Mary Jane; Textual records
  - Watt, Heather transcript and notes, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 10-4)
    Watt, Heather; Textual records
  - Draft profiles, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 10-4)
  - Draft profiles, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-24 (Archival box - standard 10-4)
  - Logbook, 1988; F-10-3-0-0-25 (Archival box - standard 10-2)
  - Allary, Donna (Carpenter), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-1; 2 audio cassettes 4 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-2943, Audio cassette OBJ-2944)
    Allary, Donna; Sound recordings; Records in electronic form (digitized)
    .wav files also available in .mp4 format.
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: C10-3-0-1.1, C10-3-0-1.2, F-10-item77, F-10-item78.
    - OBJ-2943_prt1_sideA.wav
    - OBJ-2943_prt1_sideB.wav
    - OBJ-2944_prt2_sideA.wav
    - OBJ-2944_prt2_sideB.wav
  - Brown, Sandy (Yukon: partsperson) [audio], 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-2; 1 audio cassette 2 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-2945)
    Brown, Sandy; Sound recordings; Records in electronic form (digitized)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: C10-3-0-2, F-10-item103.
    - OBJ-2945_sideA.wav
    - OBJ-2945_sideB.wav
  - Charron, Monique (electronics technician), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-3; 2 audio cassettes 3 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-2946, Audio cassette OBJ-2947)
    Charron, Monique; Sound recordings; Records in electronic form (digitized)
    OBJ-2947 Side B was blank and not digitized.
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: C-10-3-0-3.1, C-10-3-0-3.2, F-10-item125, F-10-item126.
    - OBJ-2946_prt1_sideA.wav
    - OBJ-2946_prt1_sideB.wav
    - OBJ-2947_prt2_sideA.wav
  - Courval, Marie-Andrée (Montreal: cabinet-maker), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-4; 1 audio cassette 2 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-2948)
    Courval, Marie-Andrée; Sound recordings; Records in electronic form (digitized)
    - OBJ-2948_sideA.wav
    - OBJ-2948_sideB.wav
  - Duly, Catherine (Toronto: heavy-equipment operator), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-5; 1 audio cassette 2 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-2949)
    Duly, Catherine; Sound recordings; Records in electronic form (digitized)
    - OBJ-2949_sideA.wav
    - OBJ-2949_sideB.wav
  - Duperre, Danielle (Montreal: heavy-equipment operator), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-6; 2 audio cassettes 4 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-2950, Audio cassette OBJ-2951)
    Duperre, Danielle; Sound recordings; Records in electronic form (digitized)
    - OBJ-2950_prt1_sideA.wav
    - OBJ-2950_prt1_sideB.wav
    - OBJ-2951_prt2_sideA.wav
    - OBJ-2951_prt2_sideB.wav
  - Ethier, Danielle (Winnipeg: welder), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-7; 1 audio cassette 2 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-2952)
    Ethier, Danielle; Sound recordings; Records in electronic form (digitized)
    - OBJ-2952_sideA.wav
    - OBJ-2952_SideB.wav
  - Fickes, Doreen (Whitehorse: painer), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-8; 2 audio cassettes 2 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-2953, Audio cassette OBJ-3026)
    Fickes, Doreen; Sound recordings; Records in electronic form (digitized)
    - OBJ-2953_sideA.wav
    - OBJ-2953_sideB.wav
  - Graham, Sheri (Toronto: labourer, safety inspector), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-9; 1 audio cassette 2 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-2954)
    Graham, Sheri; Sound recordings; Records in electronic form (digitized)
    - OBJ-2954_sideA.wav
    - OBJ-2954_sideB.wav
  - Irwin, Betty (Whitehorse: electronics technician), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-10 (Audio cassette OBJ-2955)
    Irwin, Betty; Sound recordings
    - OBJ-2955_sideA.wav
    - OBJ-2955_sideB.wav
  - Kaake, Sue (Toronto: electrician, foreman), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-11; 2 audio cassettes 2 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-2956, Audio cassette OBJ-2957)
    Kaake, Sue; Sound recordings; Records in electronic form (digitized)
    OBJ-2956 Side B is blank.
    - OBJ-2956_prt1_sideA.wav
    - OBJ-2957_prt2_sideA.wav
    - OBJ-2957_prt2_sideB.wav
  - Kowalchuk, Lillian (Winnipeg: plumber), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-12 (Audio cassette OBJ-2958, Audio cassette OBJ-2959, Audio cassette OBJ-3027)
    Kowalchuk, Lillian; Sound recordings
  - Kujundzic, Judy (Victoria: welder), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-13 (Audio cassette OBJ-2960, Audio cassette OBJ-2961, Audio cassette OBJ-3028, Audio cassette OBJ-3029)
    Judy Kujundzic; Sound recordings
  - Lainio, Laila (Halifax: dry-waller), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-14 (Audio cassette OBJ-2962)
    Lainio, Laila; Sound recordings
  - Lauzon, Jeannine (water-purification operator), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-15 (Audio cassette OBJ-2963, Audio cassette OBJ-2964)
    Jeannine Lauzon; Sound recordings
  - Leblanc, Jeanne (water-treatment operator), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-16 (Audio cassette OBJ-2965, Audio cassette OBJ-2966)
    Jeanne Leblanc; Sound recordings
  - Longstaff, Lori (Vancouver: tile-setter), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-17 (Audio cassette OBJ-2967, Audio cassette OBJ-2968, Audio cassette OBJ-3030, Audio cassette OBJ-3031)
    Longstaff, Lori; Sound recordings
  - Macfarlane, Sharon (painter), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-18 (Audio cassette OBJ-2969, Audio cassette OBJ-2970)
    Macfarlane, Sharon; Sound recordings
  - Millar, Jan (Whitehorse: machinist), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-19 (Audio cassette OBJ-2971, Audio cassette OBJ-2972, Audio cassette OBJ-3032)
    Millar, Jan; Sound recordings
  - Morrison, Blanche (Halifax: CN track maintenance), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-20 (Audio cassette OBJ-2973)
    Morrison, Blanche; Sound recordings
  - Newberry, Jan and Kay Collins (Toronto: carpenters), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-21 (Audio cassette OBJ-2974, Audio cassette OBJ-2975)
    Jan Newberry; Kay Collins; Sound recordings
  - Nichols, Sandra (Halifax: marine engineer), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-22 (Audio cassette OBJ-2976)
    Nichols, Sandra; Sound recordings
  - Nutt, Alison (Winnipeg: machinist/carpenter), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-23 (Audio cassette OBJ-2977, Audio cassette OBJ-2978, Audio cassette OBJ-3033)
    Nutt, Alison; Sound recordings
  - O'Toole, Mel (Halifax: carpenter), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-24 (Audio cassette OBJ-2979, Audio cassette OBJ-3034)
    Mel O'Toole; Sound recordings
  - Oakes, Pat (Toronto: ironworker/foreman), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-25 (Audio cassette OBJ-2980, Audio cassette OBJ-2981, Audio cassette OBJ-3035)
    Oakes, Pat; Sound recordings
  - Olsen, Janet (Winnipeg: industrial arts teacher), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-26 (Audio cassette OBJ-2982)
    Janet Olsen; Sound recordings
  - Pratt, Gwen (Winnipeg: carpenter), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-27 (Audio cassette OBJ-2983, Audio cassette OBJ-2984, Audio cassette OBJ-3036, Audio cassette OBJ-3037)
    Pratt, Gwen; Sound recordings
  - St. Amour, Soulange (Montreal: carpenter), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-28 (Audio cassette OBJ-2985, Audio cassette OBJ-2986)
    St. Amour, Soulange; Sound recordings
  - St. Eloi, Anne (Vancouver: plumber/pipefitter), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-29 (Audio cassette OBJ-2987, Audio cassette OBJ-3038)
    St. Eloi, Anne; Sound recordings
  - Standing, Lyn (Whitehorse: electrician), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-30 (Audio cassette OBJ-2988, Audio cassette OBJ-2989)
    Standing, Lynn; Sound recordings
  - Vaughan, Mary Jane (Halifax: shipwright/inspector), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-31 (Audio cassette OBJ-2990)
    Vaughan, Mary Jane; Sound recordings
  - Watt, Heather (Vancouver: boilermaker), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-32 (Audio cassette OBJ-2991, Audio cassette OBJ-2992, Audio cassette OBJ-3039, Audio cassette OBJ-3040)
    Watt, Heather; Sound recordings
  - Wischnewski, Cora (Montreal: apprentice carpenter), 1988; F-10-3-0-0-0-33 (Audio cassette OBJ-2993, Audio cassette OBJ-2994, Audio cassette OBJ-2995)
    Wischnewski, Cora; Sound recordings
- CBC interviews, 1990; F-10-4; 1 cm of textual records 15 sound recordings; Physical description: series contains 15 sound recordings stored on 9 audio cassettes (originals); no access copies have been made.
  In 1990 Kate Braid wrote a feature on women in trades for the CBC radio program Ideas, based on a cross-country interview trip. Series includes audio cassettes and logbook.
  - Logbook, 1990; F-10-4-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 10-2)
  - Boileau, Frank (Winnipeg: machinist), 23 January 1990; F-10-4-0-0-0-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-2996)
    Frank Boileau; Sound recordings
  - Dickinson, John (Director, School of Kinesiology, SFU), 1 February 1990; F-10-4-0-0-0-2 (Audio cassette OBJ-2996)
    Dickinson, John; Sound recordings
  - Donaldson, John (Representative, Workers' Health and Safety Committee), 18 January 1990; F-10-4-0-0-0-3 (Audio cassette OBJ-2997)
    John Donaldson; Sound recordings
  - Goebel, Faye (Toronto: carpenter), 16 January 1990; F-10-4-0-0-0-4 (Audio cassette OBJ-2998)
    Faye Goebel; Sound recordings
  - Kelly, Bill (mechanical general foreman, Ontario Hydro, Pickering), 18 January 1990; F-10-4-0-0-0-5 (Audio cassette OBJ-2997)
    Kelly, Bill; Sound recordings
  - Kujundzic, Judy (Victoria: welder), 23 January 1990; F-10-4-0-0-0-6 (Audio cassette OBJ-2999)
  - Lane, Janet, 1990; F-10-4-0-0-0-7 (Audio cassette OBJ-3000)
    Janet Lane; Sound recordings
  - McArthur-Blair, Joan, 1990; F-10-4-0-0-0-8 (Audio cassette OBJ-3000)
    MacArthur-Blair, Joan; Sound recordings
  - Nash, Scott (interviewed by Russell Kelly), 19 February 1990; F-10-4-0-0-0-9 (Audio cassette OBJ-3001)
    Scott Nash; Russell Kelly; Sound recordings
  - Nutt, Alison (Winnipeg), January 1990; F-10-4-0-0-0-10 (Audio cassette OBJ-3002)
  - O'Donnel, Bob (VP Electrical Contractors' Association of Ontario), 17 January 1990; F-10-4-0-0-0-11 (Audio cassette OBJ-2998)
    O'Donnell, Bob; Sound recordings
  - Rankin, Joyce (Winnipeg: Working Women Inc), 22 January 1990; F-10-4-0-0-0-12 (Audio cassette OBJ-3004)
    Joyce Rankin; Sound recordings
  - Watt, Heather (boilermaker), 13 January 1990; F-10-4-0-0-0-13 (Audio cassette OBJ-3003)
  - Wilkins, Kathleen (Toronto: electrician), 18 January 1990; F-10-4-0-0-0-14 (Audio cassette OBJ-3004)
    Kathleen Wilkins; Sound recordings
  - Wise, Diane (Toronto: apprenticeship administrator, Carpenters' Union), 17 January 1990; F-10-4-0-0-0-15 (Audio cassette OBJ-2998)
    Diane Wise; Sound recordings
  - Coates, Kathleen (riveter, aircraft) and Rankin, Jonnie (riveter, ships), 1990; F-10-4-0-0-0-16; 1 sound recording (Audio cassette OBJ-4796)
    Restricted in whole.
- Women in trade, 1976 - 2007; F-10-5; 62 cm of textual records 1 sound recording 1 videocassette
  Series consists of records related to Braid's work with women in trade, including training materials, conference planning and proceedings, reports, curricula, interviews and publications. Series is arranged in 4 subseries:
  1. Conference planning
  2. Reports
  3. Tradeswomen: a quarterly magazine
  4. Publications
  - Women in trade conference 'the winning ticket', 2007; F-10-5-1; 14 cm of textual records
    Series consists primarily of records relating to organizing the conference hosted by SFU on women in trades entitled "The Winning Ticket".
    - Women in trade Industry training authority, 2007; F-10-5-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 10-31)
      Open
    - Women in trade conference "A Winning Ticket", 2007; F-10-5-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 10-31)
    - Research - census information, 2007; F-10-5-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 10-31)
    - Apprenticeship statistics, 2007; F-10-5-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 10-31)
    - Women in trade conference planning "notetaker's notes", 2007; F-10-5-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 10-31)
    - Women in trade report - research, 2007; F-10-5-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 10-31)
    - A winning ticket conference planning, 2007; F-10-5-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 10-32)
  - Women in trade curricula, correspondence, reports, 1983-2007; F-10-5-2; 30 cm of textual records
    Series consists of records such as reports, studies, conference proceedings, training guides, guidelines, and curricula on women in trade.
    - Women at Work, 1983; F-10-5-2-0-0-1 (Shelf OBJ-4808)
      Moving images
      Umatic tape, 15 minutes long. Viewed May 6 2015. NFB film.
    - Papers from second international congress on women in non-traditional occupations, 1984; F-10-5-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 10-32)
    - Women in trades - pamphlets, 2000; F-10-5-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 10-32)
    - Proceedings on western regional women in trades and technology conference, 1984; F-10-5-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 10-32)
    - Report: women, native indians, visible minorities, and people with disabilities working for employers with annotations by Braid, 1990; F-10-5-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 10-32)
    - Women in trades, technology, operations farewell address by Marcia Braundy with letter from Braid, 1994; F-10-5-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 10-32)
    - Letter to Denise re proposal for women in trade program, 1991; F-10-5-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 10-32)
    - Notes from ad hoc women's committee of carpenters union, 1991; F-10-5-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 10-32)
    - Burton v Chalifour Bros harrassement in workplace reports and legal decision (Braid testified), 1993-1994; F-10-5-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 10-32)
    - Constructing change: dealing with equity issues trainer's guide, 1995; F-10-5-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 10-32)
    - Women in construction: a report on access training and retention in the construction trades, 1992; F-10-5-2-0-10 (Archival box - standard 10-32)
    - Women in trades and technology: surviving and thriving conference proceedings, 1988; F-10-5-2-0-11 (Archival box - standard 10-33)
    - Women in trades: reports, guidelines, 1980-1985; F-10-5-2-0-12 (Archival box - standard 10-33)
    - Building the future: profiles of Canadian women in trade by Kate Braid, 1989; F-10-5-2-0-13 (Archival box - standard 10-33)
    - Women in trades curricula, 1995; F-10-5-2-0-14 (Archival box - standard 10-33)
    - Women in trades curricula, 1986-1997; F-10-5-2-0-15 (Archival box - standard 10-33)
  - Tradeswomen: a quarterly magazine, 1981-1989; F-10-5-3; 6 cm of textual records
    Series consists of an incomplete run of the periodical: Tradewomen: a quarterly magazine.
    - Tradeswomen: a quarterly magazine, 1981-1983; F-10-5-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 10-33)
    - Tradeswomen: a quarterly magazine, 1984-1987; F-10-5-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 10-34)
    - Tradeswomen: a quarterly magazine, 1988-1989; F-10-5-3-0-3 (Archival box - standard 10-34)
  - Publications, F-10-5-4; 12 cm of textual records
    Series consists of publications including Braid's published report Building the Future/Profiles of Canadian Women in Trades.
    - Report of Task Force on Opportunities for Women in the Engineering Profession in British Columbia, 1976; F-10-5-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 10-5)
    - The Rally Story, 1976; F-10-5-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 10-5)
    - Women in Mining / An Exploratory Study, 1976; F-10-5-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 10-5)
    - Jobs Without Gender, 1977; F-10-5-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 10-5)
    - Positive Employment Practices Manual, [ca 1980] - [ca 1989]; F-10-5-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 10-5)
    - Working for Our Future: Opportunities for Women in Resource Development, 1980; F-10-5-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 10-5)
    - Catalogue of Training Innovations in the EC Member States, 1981; F-10-5-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 10-5)
    - A Survey of Vocation Training Initiatives for Women in the European Community, 1981; F-10-5-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 10-5)
    - New Perspectives for Women, 1983; F-10-5-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 10-5)
    - Report/Women and Work, 1985; F-10-5-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 10-5)
    - Looking Ahead/Profiles of Two Women in Trades, 1988; F-10-5-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 10-5)
    - Building the Future/Profiles of Canadian Women in Trades, 1988; F-10-5-4-0-12 (Archival box - standard 10-5)
  - CBC program on Women in Trade including interview with Kate Braid, 1982; F-10-5-0-0-0-1; 1 sound recording (Audio cassette OBJ-4797)
  - NFB program entitled Attention: Women at Work! including interview with Kate Braid, 1984; F-10-5-0-0-0-2; 1 videocassette (Videocassette: 3/4&quot; umatic OBJ-4808)
    Item is a videotape copy of a documentary about women who have nontraditional careers in such fields as architecture, transportation, and construction. Explores the views of a group of teenage girls about the factors that influence career choices. Offers advice on educational preparation for careers through the judicious choice of subjects in school.
    Pettigrew, Margaret; Henderson, Anne; National Film Board; Moving images
    - OBJ-4808-dgt.mov
- In fine form: the Canadian Book of Form Poetry, 2001-2009; F-10-6; 36 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to Braid's work on co-editing, along with Sandy Shreve, a publication on Canadian form poetry. Records include notes and contributions by form type, correspondence with writers, including PK Page, and drafts.
  Sandy Shreve's papers on the preparation of In Fine Form are located at SFU's Special Collections and Rare Books http://www.lib.sfu.ca/about/branches-depts/special-collections
  - Contract, 2004-2009; F-10-6-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 10-14)
  - Correspondence with writers, 2000-2005; F-10-6-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 10-14)
  - Editing notes, 2001-2004; F-10-6-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 10-14)
  - Editing notes, 2004; F-10-6-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 10-14)
  - Fugue, 2004; F-10-6-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 10-15)
  - Ghazal, 2004; F-10-6-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 10-15)
  - Glossary, 2004; F-10-6-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 10-15)
  - Introduction, 2004; F-10-6-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 10-15)
  - Blues, 2004; F-10-6-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 10-15)
  - Couplets, 2004; F-10-6-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 10-15)
  - Publisher - correspondence, 2003-2005; F-10-6-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 10-15)
  - Sonnet, 2001; F-10-6-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 10-15)
  - Syllabics, 2004; F-10-6-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 10-15)
  - Index of poems - round 3, 2004; F-10-6-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 10-15)
  - Index of poems - round 3, 2004; F-10-6-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 10-15)
  - "Kate's cuts", 2003; F-10-6-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 10-16)
  - Draft - under publisher, 2004; F-10-6-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 10-16)
  - Draft - under publisher, 2004; F-10-6-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 10-16)
  - Edits - April 2004, F-10-6-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 10-16)
  - Index of poems - round 3 with poems and notes, 2004; F-10-6-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 10-16)
  - Index of poems - round 3 with poems and notes, 2004; F-10-6-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 10-16)
  - In Fine Form - publication - signed by Kate Braid, 2005; F-10-6-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 10-16)
- Red Bait: Struggles of a Mine Local, 1994-2008; F-10-7; 72 cm of textual records 25 sound recordings
  Series consists of record relating to Braid's work co-authoring (along with Al King) the book Red Bait: Struggles of a Mine Local. Series includes transcripts of interviews with Al and Lillian King, drafts, edits and comments to the manuscript by various reviewers, reviews, and Al King's obituary and associated notes.
  The Al King fonds is located at the Selkirk College Archives and at UBC's Rare Books and Special Collections. A description can be found at: http://www.memorybc.ca/al-king-fonds-2 and at http://www.memorybc.ca/al-king-fonds
  - Red Bait interviews, 1992-1997; F-10-7-1; 25 sound recordings
    Series consists of interviews or recordings of Albert King on recollections of his time as a union organizer, evolution of occupational health and safety. Includes recordings of revisions recommended by King.